

Saugat Maharjan

UI/UX & Graphic Designer

saugatmaharjan11@gmail.com

J +977-9843687180



• Dhalko-17, Kathmandu

Profile

I am an UI/UX Designer from Kathmandu, Nepal who loves graphic designing with IT engineering degree, I create product from the user research to the high-fidelity design with 1 year of experience. I am highly flexible and adaptable when it comes to different projects and freelance work. My interest in design field sparked during pursuing the degree.

Besides technology, I love travelling, drawing, playing video games, listening to music, learn new things and face exciting challenges and I am a FOODIE.

Employment

Design Intern Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Associate UI/UX & Graphic Designer May 2022 - Nov 2022

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Product Designer Dec 2022 - Present

GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Education

School Leaving Certificate 2015

80.38% - First Division with Distinction

Maha Manjushree H.S School, Sitapaila, Kathamndu

2015 - 2017 **Higher Secondary Education**

65.90% - First Division

Kathmandu Model College, Bagbazzar, Kathmandu

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology 2017 - 2021

CGPA - 3.08

Nepal College of Information Technology, Balkumari, Lalitpur

Personal Details

Date of Birth

April 9, 1999

Place of Birth

Kathmandu, Nepal

Nationality

Nepali

Gender

Male

Website

www.saugatmaharjan.com

.np

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

saugat-

maharjan-471a86225/

Blood Group

O+ve

Driver's License

Yes

Certificates

Foundations of User Experience (UX)

Jun 2022

Design

Credential ID: R5JKTCWJFARF

Start the UX Design Process: Jul 2022

Empathize, Define and Ideate

Credential ID: QUMJGP9MUCES

Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Aug 2022

Prototypes

Credential ID: 9643NENPDM6J

Conduct UX Research and Test Early Sep 2022

Concepts

Credential ID: V3D9G84SHKTG

Create High-Fidelity Designs and Oct 2022

Prototypes in Figma

Credential ID: YRNQESVB83D7

Courses

Programming in C	2017
Object Oriented Programming in C++	2017
Web Technology	2018
Programming in Java	2018
Database Management System	2019
Software Engineering Fundamentals	2019
Object Oriented Design and Modeling through UML	2020
Organization and Management	2020
IP Switching and Routing (Elective I)	2021
Advanced Web Technology (Elective II)	2021

Skills

Figma

Adobe XD

Illustrator

Webflow

Photoshop

HTML/CSS

Qualities

- Active Person, Problem-Solving, Persevering, Reliable, Flexible.
- Compatible and Friendly, Teamwork and Collaborations.
- Analytical Thinking.
- Strong ability to balance multiple priorities with excellent time management skills.
- Ability to lead and work well in teams.
- Planning Research Projects.
- Excellent oral and written communication and presentation skills, ability to communicate confidently.

Internships

Design Intern

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

IntroCept, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Academic Projects

Library Management System using Python and Django

2019

First Project (4th semester)

Smart Travel Planning Application using Flutter with Dart

2020

Minor Project (6th semester)

Ghumfir: Companion Finder as

2021

an UI/UX Designer

Major Project (8th semester)

Ghumfir-Figma

Professional Projects

Flower Catalogue App 2022

Flower Catalogue App for Trendy Florist - Figma

Ghumfir 2022

Ghumfir-Figma

Employee Task Management 2022

Employee Task Management - Figma

Blog Site 2022

Blogpost Article - Figma

Cab Booking 2022

Cab Booking - Figma

Languages

Nepali

English

Newari

Hindi

Extracurricular Activities

First position in Inter-house Football

Feb 2014

Annual sports week held by school.

Second Position on Men's Cricket

Feb 2020

Held on occassion od Annual Sports Day by NCIT college.

Achievements

- Awarded by Kilagha Twa: for securing Distinction position among SLC candidates on 5th December 2015.
- Received Scholarship to study Intermediate (+2 Science) program for securing good marks in entrance exam at Kathmandu Model College.
- Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT college in 5th semester.
- Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT college in 8th semester.

Social Medias

Facebook - <u>Saugat Maharjan | Facebook</u>

Instagram - (@s.a_u.g.a.t_7)

Linkedin - Saugat Maharjan | Linkedin

Declaration

I consent to the processing of my personal data for purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying. I hereby declare that all the mentioned particulars are true about myself and take all the responsibilities for their correctness.

Hobbies

- Travelling
- Drawing
- Video Games
- Football, Futsal
- Music, Movies
- Exploring and Learning History